A racing second hand, a shooting comet!
عقرب دقائق مسرِع، مُذنّب ساقط
Let's heal hearts dried by modern society with Conan's logic!
لنعالج باستنتاجات كونان القلوب !التي جفّفها المجتمع الحديث
Today's case has Ran-neechan playing an important part!
!تتمحور قضيّة اليوم حول ران-نيتشان !حركتها وهمومها ولمعانها
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
Ran, the old man, and I attended the Izu Mystery Tour
ذهبتُ مع ران والعمّ في جولة غموض إيزو
in place of Professor Agasa, his friend, and his friend's granddaughter.
مكان البروفسور آغاسا وصديقه وحفيدته الذين لم يستطيعوا الحضور
The anonymous tour organizer would play the Night Baron
مُنظّم هذه الجولة مختبئ بين المشاركين ويلعب دور بارون الليل
and cause an incident during the tour.
ويسبّب حادثة أثناء الجولة
Whoever determines the organizer's identity gets to stay for free
من يكتشف هويّته سيمكنه الإقامة بالمجّان
and receives floppy disks containing a certain program.
ويحصل على أقراص مرنة تحوي برنامجاً ما
The attendees keep each other in check...
يراقب المشاركون بعضهم
The Night Baron pushed me off a balcony when I was all alone.
دفعني بارون الليل من شرفةٍ عندما كنتُ بمفردي
I fell into a pool.
سقطتُ في المسبح
Was this a warning? Or just part of the game?
أكان هذا تحذيراً؟ أم مجرّد جزء من اللعبة؟
And then it happened...
...ثمّ وقعت الحادثة
The Night Baron plummeted onto a bronze statue!
!سقط بارون الليل على تمثال برونزيّ
The Night Baron Murder Case (The Suspicion)
(جريمة قتل بارون الليل (جزء الاشتباه
Izu Princess Hotel
فندق الأميرة إيزو
A person wearing a mask?!
شخص يرتدي قناعاً؟
So it was the Night Baron who fell!
!كان من سقط بارون الليل بالفعل إذاً
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
Hold it, kid!
!أنت! يا ولد
Sorry!
!آسفة
Oh? Don't you live with Detective Mori?
ماذا؟ ألستَ من يعيش مع المتحرّي موري؟
Conan-kun! You know better!
!كونان-كن! لا يصحّ أن تفعل هذا
I deeply apologize!
أعتذر بشدّة
If it isn't Ran-san!
!أنت يا ران-سان
Yokomizo-san from the Saitama police department?
أأنت... يوكوميزو-سان من قسم شرطة سايتاما؟
Yep!
!نعم
But what are you doing here?
لكن لمَ أنت هنا؟
Detective Yokomizo
المحقّق يوكوميزو نُقل من محافظة سايتاما إلى محافظة شيزوكا
I transferred to Shizuoka last month.
نُقلت إلى شيزوكا الشهر الفائت
Huh?
ماذا؟
Hey, now!
!أنت
Ebara-san!
!إيبارا-سان
You know him?!
!أتعرفينه يا ران-سان؟
Yes!
أجل
He was on the same Mystery Tour as us...
كان مشاركاً معنا في جولة الغموض
Mystery Tour?!
!جولة الغموض؟
He only has one glove on...
يرتدي قفّازاً واحداً فحسب
I see.
فهمت
So the goal is to figure out who the organizer and Night Baron is.
الهدف منها هو اكتشاف هويّة المُنظّم بارون الليل إذاً
Which means the organizer was Ebara-san here.
ما يعني أنّ المُنظّم كان إيبارا-سان هنا
A suicide? An accident? Or maybe a--
...انتحار؟ حادث؟ أم
Say, where is Detective Mori?
بالمناسبة، أين المتحرّي موري؟
Well, he's--
...إنّه
In the pub on the 2nd floor.
في حانة الطابق الثاني
Huh?!
!ماذا؟
Kamijo-san!
!كاميجو-سان
Anyway, let's have a talk with him!
!لنتكلّم في الموضوع معه بأيّ حال
Alright. Come on, Conan-kun!
حسناً، تعال يا كونان-كن
This way!
!من هنا
Wait for me!
!انتظراني
Tears?
دموع؟
Princess Hotel 2F Pub Emerald
الطابق الثاني لفندق الأميرة (حانة (الزمّرد
What a time for Dad to get plastered!
!نام ثملاً في مكان كهذا
I see...
...هكذا إذاً
What?! Ebara-san fell off dressed as the Night Baron?!
ماذا؟! سقط إيبارا-سان ولقي حتفه !وهو يرتدي رداء بارون الليل؟
Yes, according to eyewitnesses, he fell at precisely 10:00!
أجل، وفقاً للشهود فقد سقط عند تمام العاشرة
What's with the hands?
لمَ تفعل هذا بيديك؟
It's your smell...
...حسناً... الرائحة
10:00, huh?
العاشرة إذاً؟
What is it?
ما الأمر؟
Whoa! It's already this late?!
!عجباً! تأخّر الوقت لهذا الحد؟
So, did you check Room 2101, where he was staying?
إذاً، أتفقدتم الغرفة 2101 التي كان يقيم فيها؟
We tried to, but we couldn't get inside.
كنّا نحاول ذلك، لكن لم نستطع الدخول
A security lock on the inside...
قفل أمان مربوط في الداخل
Cut through it!
اكسروه فوراً
Okay! We're in!
!حسناً، فُتح
There are clothes here.
توجد ثياب هنا
Those are the ones he was wearing today.
هذه التي كان يرتديها إيبارا-سان اليوم
He even left his room key here.
ترك مفتاح غرفته هنا حتّى
Come to think of it, he was pretty drunk...
بالمناسبة، كان ثملاً جدّاً
The window's open.
النافذة مفتوحة
And there's a veranda outside...
وتوجد شرفة في الخارج
It would appear this is where he fell from.
يبدو أنّه سقط من هنا
Careful, Detective Mori.
انتبه يا مُتحرّي موري
This was just a simple accident.
هذا... مجرّد حادث
An accident?!
!حادث؟
No doubt about it. There's a glove in the railing.
لا شكّ في الأمر، يوجد قفّاز عالق بالسور
Eh?!
!ماذا؟
He probably tried to climb down the veranda in that costume
حاول النزول غالباً من الشرفة في ردائه ذاك
to scare the attendee in the room below.
لإخافة المشاركين في الغرفة أسفلها
But he screwed up and fell to his death.
لكنّه تعثّر ولقي حتفه
I dunno...
...أتساءل عن ذلك
This is the 21st floor.
هذا الطابق 21
Would he really try to go down without a rope?
هل يحاول النزول دون حبل حقّاً؟
Plus, the key was inside the room.
كما كان مفتاح الغرفة في الداخل
If he did make it to the room below and then left through it,
إذا نجح في النزول للغرفة السفليّة ثمّ خرج منها
he would've needed the key to get back in here.
فسيحتاج المفتاح للعودة هنا
Quiet, you!
!اخرس
My pen!
!قلم الحبر خاصتي
Anyway, let me have a look at the body.
بأيّ حال، دعني أتفقد الجثّة
Right.
حسناً
Seeing it won't change anything, though.
رغم أنّ رؤيتها لن تغيّر شيئاً غالباً
Oh, man...
...يا للفظاعة
So he fell twenty-one stories onto that statue...
...سقط من 21 طابقاً إذاً على ذاك التمثال
Has anyone gotten near the body?
هل اقترب أحد من الجثّة؟
No, sir. Aside from us, only one other person has touched him.
كلا يا محقّق يوكوميزو، لم يلمس أحدٌ الجثّة سوانا نحن الشرطة وشخص واحد
That little boy there.
ذاك الصبيّ
That brat again?!
ذاك الولد مُجدداً؟
What're you doing, Conan-kun?
ما الذي تفعله يا كونان-كن؟
I can't find the pen that I dropped...
لا أجد قلم البحر الذي سقط منّي
Is it true that Ebara-san was the one who fell, Mori-san?
أصحيحٌ أنّ إيبارا-سان سقط لحتفه يا موري-سان؟
No question about it. It was Ebara Tokio.
لا شكّ في الأمر، كان إيبارا توكيو
And he had a mask on.
وكان يرتدي قناعاً
A mask?!
قـ-قناع؟
I see. So he was the tour organizer and the Night Baron.
فهمت، كان هو مُنظّم الجولة وبارون الليل إذاً
I knew it. I always thought he was suspicious.
عرفت، بدا لي مثيراً للشبهة
Knock it off. This isn't the time.
توقّفي، ليس هذا وقته
Though it is disturbing that the immortal Night Baron would perish...
موت بارون الليل المنيع نهاية بائسة بحقّ
Who are these people?
من هؤلاء الأشخاص؟
Members of the same tour I'm on.
أعضاء في نفس الجولة معي
But why would Ebara-san--
...لكن لمَ إيبارا-سان
It was just an accident.
كانت حادثة فحسب
An accident?
حادثة؟
Yes. He fell off the veranda trying to scare you all.
أجل، سقط من الشرفة وهو يحاول النزول لإخافتكم
At any rate, the Night Baron has died.
بأيّ حال، مات بارون الليل
Now the tour is over.
انتهت الجولة الآن
Huh?
!عجباً
Weird. What's with this necktie?
غريب، ما خطب ربطة العنق هذه؟
Look at the knot.
انظروا لهذه العقدة
The knot?
العقدة؟
It's backwards!
!إنّها مقلوبة! مقلوبة
But this could be normal for him.
لكن قد تكون هذه عادته
I have a necktie of his.
ربطة عنقه معي
Here.
هاك
Where'd you get that?
كيف حصلت عليها؟
She said he forgot it.
قالت أنّه نسيها
It's true! This tie's knot is normal!
!بالفعل، عقدة ربطة العنق هذه طبيعية
Huh?
!عجباً
Huh?! Is there something else?!
!ماذا؟! أهناك شيء آخر؟
He's wearing his belt weird, too.
حزامه في وضع غريب أيضاً
See? It's upside-down.
انظروا، إنّه مقلوب
He's not good with accessories, is he?
هذا الشخص لا يجيد ارتداء الكماليّات
This is too unusual, Mori-san.
هذا غريبٌ فوق المعتاد يا موري-سان
Yeah. He didn't put these clothes on.
أجل، لم يرتد الملابس بنفسه
Someone put them on him!
هناك من ألبسه
Which means Ebara-san was pushed off the 21st floor
ما يعني أنّ إيبارا-سان دُفع من غرفة الطابق الواحد والعشرين
by the real Night Baron.
من قِبل بارون الليل الحقيقيّ
In other words, the homicidal Night Baron is still among us!
!أي أنّ بارون الليل القاتل لا يزال بيننا
It appears we must ask where each of you were
يبدو أنّ علينا استجوابكم عن حجج غيابكم
when Ebara-san fell at 10:00 pm.
وقت سقوط إيبارا-سان عند العاشرة
Go to the front desk and ask them to prepare a room for questioning.
اذهب لمكتب الاستقبال واطلب منهم تجهيز غرفة للاستجواب
Yes, sir!
!حاضر
What should we do with the body and the costume?
ماذا نفعل بالجثّة والزيّ؟
Good question.
...حسناً
Let's set him in the office until we're done with the questioning.
فلنبقه في مكتب الفندق حتى ننهي الاستجواب
Understood.
حسناً
Interrogation Room - Authorized Personnel Only
غرفة استجواب للأشخاص المعنيّين فقط
I see.
هكذا إذاً
So you were in the observation lounge with Ran and Conan?
كنت في صالة المراقبة رفقة ران وكونان عند العاشرة إذاً؟
Maeda Satoru (30)
أجل، انفصلتُ عنهما
10:00 that I left them.
بعد العاشرة بقليل
It's the truth, Dad!
!هذه الحقيقة يا أبي
But you were the one who looked at the time, right?
لكنّك كنت من نظر للساعة، صحيح يا مايدا-سان؟
Yeah...
...أجل
Alright. Call in the next person.
حسناً، لا بأس. استدعوا الشخص التالي
My alibi is airtight!
حجّة غيابي مُحكمة
After all, I was in the pub with this man the whole time!
!فقد كنتُ في الحانة مع هذا الرجل وقت الحادثة
Right, Mr. Detective?
صحيح حضرة المتحرّي؟
Y-Yeah!
نـ-نعم
But didn't he get dead-drunk?
لكن ألم يغلبه الثمل؟
Yeah, but...
...صـ-صحيح، لكن
Okay. Next!
حسناً، التالي
We were in an open-air restaurant
كنّا في المطعم المفتوح
near where Ebara-san fell.
حيث سقط إيبارا-سان
lsn't that right, Shizue-san?
أليس كذلك يا شيزوي-سان؟
Yes, sir.
بلى سيّدي
Can anyone vouch for this?
أهناك من يشهد بذلك؟
It was such a commotion that I'm unsure people would remember us.
حسناً... كانت الجلبة كبيرة فلا أدري إن كان هناك من يتذكّرنا
But with the way he died, I can't say I blame them.
لكن بطريقة موته، الأمر ليس مُستغرباً
Bring in the next one!
!استدعوا التالي
I was in my room reading my
كنتُ في غرفتي أقرأ رسائل بريد إلكترونية
Konno Shiro (28)
على الحاسوب من التاسعة وخمس وأربعون إلى بعد العاشرة
The hotel's records should prove that.
يُفترض أنّ سجلّات الفندق ستثبت ذلك
But you didn't speak with anyone, correct?
لكنك لم تتكلم مع أحد، صحيح؟
Oh, but I did. With my computer.
بلى، مع حاسوبي
Yikes!
ماذا؟
Call in the next person.
استدعوا التالي
You were alone in your room, too?
كنتِ بمفردك في غرفتك طوال الوقت، صحيح؟
Yes.
أجل
I was watching TV alone until
كنتُ أشاهد التلفاز وحدي
Satoru returned after 10:00.
حتّى رجع ساتورو بعد العاشرة
So I take it you have nobody to vouch for you?
يعني أنّ لا أحد يشهد لك بذلك؟
I can describe what the movie was about, though...
يـ-يمكنني وصف الفيلم الذي كنتُ أشاهده مع ذلك
There was a bomb in a skyscraper--
...كانت هناك قنبلة في ناطحة سحاب
Nope. That won't work as proof.
كلا، لن يكفي ذلك كدليل
I can't believe they made me guard him alone!
!هذا قاسٍ! يجعلونني أحرسه بمفردي
I hope they finish their questioning soon!
!آمل أن ينهوا الاستجواب سريعاً
That detective and your father really tick me off!
!أثار والدك وذاك المحقق أعصابي حقّاً
I bet they think I did it!
لا بدّ أنّهما يعتقدانني المجرمة
That's not true!
!هذا ليس صحيحاً
There's tons of other suspicious people!
هناك الكثير من الأشخاص المشبوهين غيري
Indeed...
...بالفعل
Is my shift over?
هل انتهت مناوبتي؟
Yeah? Huh?
أجل؟
Everyone on the tour has a flimsy alibi.
حجج غياب جميع المشاركين في الجولة ضعيفة
Did you maybe order room service when you were in your room?
هل طلبتِ من خدمة الغرف شيئاً عندما كنتِ في غرفتك؟
I would've already said so if I had.
لو فعلت لقلتُ ذلك
How did the killer leave after pushing Ebara-san off his veranda?
كيف غادر القاتل بعدما دفع إيبارا-سان من شرفة الغرفة؟
The room had its security lock set!
كان قفل الأمان مربوطاً، فكيف؟
You called the front desk?!
اتّصلتِ بمكتب الاستقبال؟
When was that?!
متى كان ذلك؟
The hotel keeps records of when calls are made from rooms!
!يحتفظ الفندق بسجلّات مكالمات الغرف ووقتها
That means your alibi is--
...أي أنّ حجّة غيابك
No way!
!مُحال
Stand back!
!تراجعي
Stop!
!توقّف
What're you doing?! He's getting away! Ran-neechan!
ما الذي تفعلينه يا ران-نيتشان؟ !إنّه يهرب! ران-نيتشان
Ran-neechan!
!ران-نيتشان
Interrogation Room
!ماذا؟ ظهر؟
Why the heck didn't you catch him?!
!حمقاء! لمَ لم تمسكي به؟
Sorry! I was in shock!
آسفة، كنتُ مصدومة
Detective Yokomizo!
!محقّق يوكوميزو
What happened?
ما الأمر؟
He was collapsed in the room with the body!
كان فاقداً للوعي في غرفة حراسة الجثّة
It appears he was hit by someone!
!يبدو أنّ أحداً ضربه
Eh?! And the body?!
ماذا؟ ما حلّ بالجثّة؟
It's fine, but the Night Baron costume is gone!
!إنّها بخير، لكنّ زيّ بارون الليل اختفى
The Night Baron costume?!
زيّ بارون الليل؟
Mori-san...
...موري-سان
Detective Yokomizo!
!محقّق يوكوميزو
What is it?!
ما الأمر؟
The Night Baron's in the pool!
!بارون الليل في المسبح
What?!
!ماذا؟
The mask, hat, wig, and cape!
!القناع والقبعة، والشعر المستعار والمعطف
So what about the person wearing it?!
ماذا عن مرتديه؟
Where could they be?
أ-أين يمكن أن يكون؟
Probably up there. They tossed it from that balcony.
في الأعلى غالباً، رماه من تلك الشرفة
Why did the killer show up at the elevators?
لمَ ظهر القاتل أمام المصعد بذاك الزيّ؟
If they needed to go up, they would've used the stairs to go unseen.
إذا أراد الصعود للأعلى، كان يمكنه استعمال الأدراج دون أن يراه أحد
And why did they have to wear the costume,
ولمَ كان عليه ارتداء الزيّ؟
not to mention risk being caught trying to steal it?!
فضلاً عن مُخاطرته بنفسه لسرقته
His methods are too aggressive!
أسلوبه طائش جدّاً
Could these latest things have been unplanned?!
أيمكن أنّ هذه الحادثة لم تكن ضمن مخططاته؟
Okay! We need to re-question them!
!حسناً، سنعيد الاستجواب
Round up all the suspects!
!اجمعوا المشتبه بهم
Yes, sir!
!حاضر
You were all in your rooms, and you have no witnesses!
كنتم كلّكم في غرفكم، ولا أحد يشهد لكم
Which means none of you have alibis for when
ما يعني أنّ لا أحد منكم
Sayama-san and the others were attacked! Correct?
يملك حجّة غياب عندما تعرضت ساياما-سان والبقيّة للهجوم! صحيح؟
Hold on, Detective.
تمهّل حضرة المحقق
You told us not to leave our rooms, and that's just what we did!
،أخبرتنا ألّا نغادر غرفنا حتّى تصلنا تعليمات وذلك ما اتّبعناه
Yes. We only did as you asked.
أجل، أصغينا لما أُمرنا به فحسب
We're not stupid enough to ignore the police.
لسنا أغبياء بحيث نتجاهل الشرطة
That's right.
تماماً
Akiko-san and Maeda-san share the same room.
تتشارك أكيكو-سان الغرفة مع مايدا-سان
You didn't check if they were there or not?
لم تتفقّدوا إن كان هناك؟
There was no time to!
!لم يكن لدينا وقت
We all came right away to report about the Night Baron!
!أتينا للتبليغ عن حادثة بارون الليل فوراً
Right?
صحيح؟
Yeah.
بـ-بلى
At any rate, we'll need to check all your rooms.
بأيّ حال، علينا تفقد كلّ غرفكم
Yours first, Maeda-san. That alright?
سنبدأ بك يا مايدا-سان، أتمانع؟
Yes.
كلا
Nothing seems out of the ordinary-- What the...
!لا شيء مثير للريبة بالتحديد... ماذا؟
What's the big idea?!
!ما الذي تفعله؟
Just letting some air in!
!أقوم بتهوية الغرفة فحسب
That stupid kid!
!تبّاً، ذاك الشقيّ
Just to be sure, please empty your pockets.
أفرغوا ما بجيوبكم من باب الحيطة
I have this room's layout figured out.
فهمتُ تصميم هذه الغرفة
Ebara-san fell from that veranda...
سقط إيبارا-سان من تلك الشرفة
Yes. The killer dressed him up as the Night Baron
أجل، ألبسه القاتل رداء بارون الليل
and pushed him off to make it look like an accident!
ودفعه بحيث يبدو حادثاً
But the security lock was set in the room where it happened!
لكنّ قفل الأمان كان مربوطاً في غرفة إيبارا-سان
In other words, the killer didn't leave through the door afterward.
ما يعني أنّ القاتل لم يغادر من الباب بعد دفعه لإيبارا-سان
Meaning this was a locked-room murder!
!أي أنّ هذه كانت جريمة قتل غرفة مقفلة
The veranda is the only other way out of the room...
الشرفة كانت المخرج الوحيد للقاتل إن استطاع الهرب
But going from there into this room is impossible.
لكن النزول من هناك والقدوم لهذه الغرفة أشبه بالمستحيل
Huh? What's this medicine?
ماذا؟ ما هذا الدواء؟
Ordinary sleeping pills.
مجرد حبوب تنويم
I always carry them with me for my insomnia. That a problem?
أعاني أرقاً فأحملها معي دوماً، أهي مشكلة؟
Can I see?
أيمكنني أن أرى؟
Okay, let's go to the next room.
حسناً، لنذهب للغرفة التالية
You won't find anything, Detective.
لن تجد شيئاً مهما بحثتم حضرة المحقّق
We're just making sure.
علينا اتّخاذ كلّ الإجراءات
Him again!
!ذاك الشقيّ مُجدداً
The veranda he fell from is directly above...
الشرفة التي سقط منها إيبارا-سان فوق هذه تماماً
It might be possible to climb down here...
...ربما من الممكن النزول هنا
Why do you keep following me?!
!لمَ تتبعني باستمرار؟
I thought I'd watch your great detective skills in action!
!أردتُ رؤية تحرياتك العظيمة بعينيّ
Oh, okay! In that case, pay close attention!
!هكذا إذاً، افتح عينيك وراقب جيّداً في تلك الحالة
There are no signs of the window being broken.
لا علامات على تحطّم النافذة
Guess he can be cute sometimes!
ربما به بعض الظرافة
Was this window always locked, Mister?
أكانت هذه النافذة مقفلة دوماً يا جدّ؟
My eyes are bad. Can you answer, Shizue-san?
لا أستطيع الرؤية، أيمكنك الإجابة يا شيزوي-سان؟
Of course it was. I check it each time we leave.
بالطبع، كنتُ أتحقق من قفلها كلّما غادرنا
Konno-san's room is next.
غرفة كونّو-سان هي التالية
I've heard that he was suspected of using his bank's computers
سمعتُ أنّه تحت شبهة استعمال حواسيب مصرفه دون إذن
without permission and was thus demoted.
فتمّ خفض منصبه
He may have wanted to see the Baron the most of all.
لعلّه أكثر من أراد لقاء البارون
Huh?
ماذا؟
It's simply a rumor, though.
لكنّها مجرّد شائعة
So that old man told you that?
أخبركم ذاك العجوز بذلك إذاً؟
Who's he to talk? He's the one who hates the Night Baron the most.
كيف له الكلام؟ فهو أكثر من يكره بارون الليل
What do you mean?!
!ما قصدك؟
After all, the son he so dutifully raised was murdered by the virus.
هذه الحقيقة، فالابن الذي شاقى في تربيته قُتل بالفيروس
Come to think of it, he did mention that...
...صحيح، قال ذاك العجوز
The Night Baron. Hearing that name brings back memories
بارون الليل، سماع ذاك الاسم يرجع لي الذكريات
of my son who died four years ago...
ذكريات ابني الذي مات قبل 4 أعوام
A virus? His son died of an illness?
فيروس؟ مات ابنه من مرض؟
What's that have to do with the Night Baron?!
!ما علاقة ذلك ببارون الليل؟
That's a good question...
...لا أعرف تلك التفاصيل
Are you playing dumb?!
!أتتحامق معي؟
Mori-san...
...موري-سان
Please stop! I'll give you some special information!
!توقّف رجاءً! سأخبرك بمعلومة خاصّة
This is the closest window to the veranda, but there's no way across.
هذه أقرب نافذة للشرفة، لكن القفز لها مستحيل
With Kamijo-san?!
!كاميجو-سان؟
They were married.
كانا متزوّجين
Though I hear they divorced three years ago.
رغم أنّي سمعت أنّهما تطلّقا قبل ثلاثة أعوام
That's right. The late Ebara Tokio was my husband.
صحيح، إيبارا توكيو الراحل كان زوجي
But that was three years ago... when I learned he was a hacker.
،لكن كان ذلك قبل ثلاثة أعوام عندما عرفت أنّه كان مخترقاً
Hacker?
مخترق؟
A criminal who steals computer data!
!مجرم يسرق بيانات الحاسوب
Everyone who uses a computer loathes hackers!
!كلّ من يستعملون الحواسيب يكرهون المخترقين
I'm relieved that he's dead.
أشعر بالارتياح لموته
Ah, yes.
بالمناسبة
I believe Sayama Akiko-san's brother ran a small software company.
أظنّ أخا ساياما أكيكو-سان كان يدير شركة برمجيات حاسوب صغيرة
Which means she's no exception, either.
ما يعني أنّها ليست خارج الشبهة
Meaning that everyone on the tour had a reason to kill him.
أي أنّ جميع المشاركين في الجولة كانوا يملكون دافعاً لقتله
Right, Detective?
حضرة المحقق
Oh? These are the same pills that Akiko-san had...
...ماذا؟ هذه نفس الحبوب التي كانت مع أكيكو-سان
Are these also--
...أهذه أيضاً
Say, what are these pills for?
أخبريني، ما هذه الحبوب؟
Hey! Don't touch my things!
!لـ-لحظة! لا تلمس أغراضي
Is it cold medicine?
أهو دواء زكام؟
Y-Yes, that's right...
...أجل، صحيح
Oh, I thought they were sleeping pills. Guess not.
ظننتُها حبوب منوّمة، ربما اشتبهت عليّ
Alright, you!
!أنت
What are you blabbing about now?! Go get in bed, kid!
!ما الذي تثرثر به؟! ارجع لغرفتك يا طفل ونم
I didn't check the room's layout yet!
!لم أتفقد تصميم الغرفة بعد
Ah, well. It's the same layout as Konno-san's room downstairs.
حسناً، لا يهم. فهي غالباً بنفس تخطيط غرفة كونّو-سان بالأسفل
Well, looking at everyone's rooms, we get...
...بالنظر لغرف الجميع
Ebara - Room 2101
إيبارا- غرفة 2101
Kamijo - Room 2102
إيبارا - غرفة 2101 كاميجو - غرفة 2102
Kaneshiro & Hayashi - Room 2001
كانيشيرو وهاياشي - غرفة 2001
Konno - Room 2002
كونّو - غرفة 2002
Maeda & Sayama - Room 1901
مايدا وساياما - غرفة 1901
Body
هذا ما نجده
...as a result.
الجثّة
So the only possible escape from Ebara-s an's veranda
أي أنّ المخرج الوحيد من شرفة إيبارا-سان
was through Kaneshiro-san and Hayashi-san's room...
كان عبر غرفة كانيشيرو-سان وهاياشي-سان
What do we do with this?
ما نفعل بهذه؟
I'm not sure. It's a piece of the security lock.
لا أدري، إنّها قطعة من قفل الأمان
Oh, yeah. Ebara-san's room is on this floor, too.
صحيح، غرفة إيبارا-سان بهذا الطابق أيضاً
Hey, there's something on the tip...
هناك شيء على الطرف
It's cellophane tape!
!شريط لاصق شفّاف
Wait a minute! Could this be--
...لحظة! أيمكن أن
He dodged all of my kicks with no effort at all!
تفادى كلّ ركلاتي بمرونة ودون أيّ جهد إضافي
The only suspect who could've done that was... him!
الوحيد بين المُشتبه بهم القادر على ذلك... هو دون سواه
What should I do?!
ماذا عليّ أن أفعل؟
Tell me, Shinichi!
!أخبرني يا شينتشي
Shinichi!
!شينتشي
Open up, Ran-neechan!
!افتحي يا ران-نيتشان
Conan-kun! What's the matter?
كونان-كن، ما الخطب؟
The security lock was set.
كان قفل الأمان مربوطاً
That's strange. I don't remember locking it.
غريب، لا أتذكر ربطه
Success!
!نجحت التجربة
Huh? Are you crying?
ماذا؟ أتبكين؟
No! Some tears came out when I yawned.
كلا! دموع من التثاؤب فقط
Well, I'm leaving for a bit!
!سأغادر قليلاً
At this time of night?!
في هذا الوقت المتأخّر؟
I'll be back soon!
!سأرجع سريعاً
Oh, it's you.
إنّه ذاك الصبيّ
You should be asleep, little boy.
عليك النوم الآن يا فتى
Don't worry about it.
لا تهتمّ
Using that trick, anyone could have killed him!
كان بمقدور أيّ أحد ارتكاب الجريمة باستعمال تلك الحيلة
I'll have to check each of their alibis...
عليّ مراجعة كلّ حجج غيابهم
Hey, you hear about Misawa-san?
بالمناسبة، أسمعت ما حصل مع ميساوا-سان؟
About how the killer knocked him out in the office with the body?
ضربه القاتل في غرفة حراسة الجثّة، صحيح؟
But isn't Misawa-san a karate expert?
لكن أليس ميساوا-سان خبيراً في الكاراتيه؟
Yeah! Best in the department!
بلى، الأقوى في قسمنا
Even if he was caught off guard...
...مهما باغته الفاعل
Hey, now!
...لحظة
Could the killer be--
...أيمكن أنّ القاتل
Huh? Conan-kun?
ماذا؟ كونان-كن؟
Alright, who set the security lock?!
من ربط قفل الأمان؟
I locked it from the outside!
ربطتُه من الخارج
It locked!
!رُبط
That would seal the room and make it look like an accident!
!هكذا تكون الغرفة مقفلة، ويمكن جعله يبدو حادثاً
I found an alibi for him!
!وجدتُ حجّة غياب له
Hold on a second!
لحظة
There's one place where the wind is--
...كان هناك مكان واحد حيث الريح
The Night Baron Murder Case (The Solution)
(جريمة قتل بارون الليل (جزء الحلّ
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Wind through the buildings.
رياح عبر المباني
Next episode the case is finally solved. You're the culprit!
!الحلقة القادمة جزء الحلّ أخيراً
Me again?
أنا مُجدّداً؟